Guide to the Cornell University Cooperative Extension records, 1915-2009.
Cornell University Cooperative Extension records, 1915-2009.
- Series IV. Initiatives, Plans, Projects, Reports
  - New York City Extension - Nutrition and Health Education for Families, 2009 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - New York City Extension - Annual Reports, 2007, 2009 (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - New York City Extension - Kitchens of Faith, 2008, 2009 (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - New York City Extension - Farmers Market Nutrition Program - Professional Development, Evaluation Plans, Logic Models, 2007-2008 (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - New York City Extension - EFNEP, ESNY, Project Bridge - Evaluation Plans, Logic Model, 2007-2008 (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - Community Resource Development Narrative Reports
    - Narrative Reports, EDA and RRD Committees, 1965-1968 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Narrative Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Narrative Reports, 1970-1973 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Narrative Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Narrative Reports, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Narrative Reporting, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Narrative Highlights, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - National CRD Leaders Workshop, St. Louis, MO, 1978-04-17-1978-04-20 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Narrative Report, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Narrative Topics- Counties, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - National CRD Evaluation, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 30)
      Spring
    - Narrative Report, 1979-1980 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Narrative Reporting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Annual Narrative Report of Accomplishments, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Annual Narrative Report of Accomplishments, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 34)
- Series V. DVDs, Video Tapes and Audio Cassette Tapes
  - Assistant Director Candidate Seminars, Undated; V-619 (Box 48)
  - CCE: Video Report, Undated; V-620 (Box 48)
  - Revitalizing Cornell Cooperative Extension II, Undated; V-621 (Box 48)
  - "Principles of Parenting: Getting Young Children Ready to Learn", Undated; V-6913 (Box 88)
  - "Children in Poverty: What's To Be Done", Undated; V-6914 (Box 88)
  - "Teens, Spending and Consumer Socialization" by Josephine Swanson, Undated; V-6916 (Box 88)
  - "Family Grocery Shopping and Family Resource Management", Undated; V-6917 (Box 88)
  - Statutory Colleges at Cornell: Service to the State, Nation and World, Undated; V-6932 (Box 88)
  - Power of Youth, Undated; V-6934 (Box 88)
  - From Welfare to Well-Being, Undated; V-6935 (Box 88)
  - Food, Agriculture, and Health Policy Education - The Northeast Network, 1991; V-7100 (Box 1)
  - Reaching the Top: Three Success Stories, 1991-04-01; V-622 (Box 48)
  - Raising Responsible Teens, 1993-05; V-6929 (Box 88)
  - Balancing Work and Family, 1994-05; V-6930 (Box 88)
  - Dean Sutphin Interview, 1994-05-17; V-623 (Box 48)
  - "Addressing Public Issues Through Education", 1995; V-6918 (Box 88)
  - Janet Clay White Lecture:A View From the Inside Out- Participants' Views of Food Assistance, 1995-09; V-6931 (Box 88)
  - "Champions of Change: Child Nutrition Personnel", 1995-10-25; V-6962 (Box 88)
  - Fabric/Flight Connection-examines the role of textile materials in contemporary and historic aviation, 1996; V-5930 (Box 48)
  - Stepping Into A Virtual World: Design and Environmental Analysis, 1996-08; V-624 (Box 48)
  - Family Resiliency, 1996-09; V-6926 (Box 88)
  - Creating Positive Spaces for School-Aged Child Care, 1996-09; V-6927 (Box 88)
  - County Planning for Welfare Reform, 1996-10; V-6928 (Box 88)
  - Family Day Care Projects Training - SUNY ECETP, 1997; V-6915 (Box 88)
  - Communicating with your Health Care Provider, 1998; V-6249 (Box 66)
  - Assuring Success for the Class of 2016: The Effect of Parent-Child Interaction on Early Child Development, 1998-01; V-6923 (Box 88)
  - Programming for Families Affected by Welfare Reform, 1998-03; V-6924 (Box 88)
  - Families Affected by Welfare Reform, 1998-03; V-6925 (Box 88)
  - Understanding Youth Assets and Family Resiliency, 1998-05; V-6919 (Box 88)
  - Welfare Reform Two years Later, 1998-07; V-6920 (Box 88)
  - Moving People to Action: Facilitating Behavior Change in Youth and Adults, 1998-09; V-6921 (Box 88)
  - Exploring the State of Poverty, 1998-11; V-6922 (Box 88)
  - Cooking up Fun? - a Pyramid of Snacks, 1998; V-6963 (Box 88)
  - Safe and Supportive Communities, 1999-06; V-6933 (Box 88)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension Promo, 1999-03-05; V-6964 (Box 88)
  - "If it hadn't been for Cornell Cooperative Extension...", 1999-09; V-625 (Box 48)
  - 4-H External Review: Countdown to Action, 1999-02-26; V-626 (Box 48)
  - Second Tuesday- "The State of Extension", 1999-05-11; V-627 (Box 48)
  - "Second Tuesday- The State of Extension", 1999-05-11; V-628 (Box 48)
  - "Second Tuesday" Cooperative Extension- Interviews, 1999-09-14; V-629 (Box 48)
  - "Second Tuesday", 1999-11-09; V-630 (Box 48)
    Margaret Smith and Stephen Kresovich:
    (1)Genetically engineered foods issues
    (2)Last week's CCE advisory council meeting
    (3)Update on federal budget and latest meeting on NE Dairy Compact
  - CCE- Suffolk County - Annual, 2000; V-631 (Box 48)
  - CCESN "Second Tuesday", 2000-01-11; V-632 (Box 48)
    Interviews:
    (1)Patsy Brannon
    (2)Ed Hershey
    (3)Ed Harwood
    (4)Merrill Ewert
  - "4-H Strategic Plan" Videoconference", 2000-04-15; V-633 (Box 48)
  - Managing at the Edge of Change, 2000-05; V-6936 (Box 88)
  - "Second Tuesday", 2000-05-09; V-634 (Box 48)
    (1)Responsiveness
    (2)Respect for Patrons
    (3)Academic Neutrality
    (4)Accessibility
    (5)Integration
    (6)Coordination
    (7)Resource Partnership
    Merrill Ewert, Review past year, Reasons for celebration, Agenda for next year
  - "Second Tuesday", 2000-09-12; V-635 (Box 48)
    New Asst. Director of 4-H Youth Development: Kathanne Kress, Video Tape: Historical perspective of Cornell Cooperative Extension, Update and Discussion of West Nile, Future of Cornell Cooperative Extension, New Dean of Agriculture: Susan Henry
  - "Second Tuesday", 2000-11-14; V-636 (Box 48)
    Programs Problems Issues w/Cornell Cooperative Extension, Volunteer involvement policy, Statewide community food security initiative, Cornell Cooperative Extension revitalization plan, Genetically engineered organisms- public issues education project to provide objective information resources about genetic engineering
  - "Second Tuesday", 2001-01-09; V-637 (Box 48)
    Joe Swanson: How you can be part of Human Ecology's strategic planning for extension and outreach, Latest on professional excellence- part of the Cornell Cooperative Extension revitalization plan, Ken Hillary- latest on new classification and compensation system, Final draft of revitalization plan, Preview of Cornell Cooperative Extension Civil Rights Compliance Review- Glenn Applebee (CCE Asst. Dir.)
  - Healthy Families, Healthy Communities, 2001-02; V-6937 (Box 88)
  - Get Fresh! At Your Farmers Market -Apples, Potatoes, Broccoli, Squash - in English, 2001; V-6965 (Box 88)
  - Get Fresh! At Your Farmers Market - Apples, Potatoes, Broccoli, Squash - in Spanish, 2001; V-6966 (Box 88)
  - Get Fresh! At Your Farmers Market-Peaches, Kale, Carrots, Cabbage - in Spanish, 2001; V-6967and V-6968 (Box 88)
  - "Second Tuesday", 2001-03-13; V-638 (Box 48)
    New Cornell Logo, Betsy Bin: Good Ag Practice/Food Safety Program Begins on Farm, Rod Hoy and Andy Turner - Define Cornell Cooperative Extension Education of the Future, JC Shaver: Committing to Excellence, Merrill Ewert: Agricultural Initiative- where we stand without getting our system wired through improved communication technology, Cecilia Cowles: Visually Identity program/New Logo
  - "Second Tuesday", 2001-05-08; V-639 (Box 48)
    Patsy Brannon-Dean of Human Ecology, Susan Henry- Dean of Ag/Life Science, Hunter Rawlings-Cornell President, 3rd Annual State of Extension, Revitalization Process, Merrill Ewert, Review of Year, Causes for Celebration, Agenda for following year
  - "Talking to Children about our National Tragedy", 2001-09-20; V-1499
  - CCE Week - Farm to Table Urban Delights, 2001-09; V-6938 (Box 88)
  - Nutrition Program - Cornell Extension - Auburn Residential, 2005; V-6969 (Box 88)
  - Contemporary Pies - Leader Training, V-6970 (Box 88)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension Video Report, V-6971 (Box 88)
  - Anne Murphy's Hat Trick from "Low Income Recruitment and Training", V-6972 (Box 88)
  - Interviews with past Cornell Cooperative Extension Employees and their Experiences: Rachel Merritt, Natalie Crowe, Mildred Essick, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    3 Audio cassette Tapes and Transcripts: Mildred Essick, Emily Graham, Fred Morris
  - Healthy Homes: Assessing Your Indoor Environment - produced by Joseph Laquatra, 2006; DVD-1514 (Box 48)
  - Careers in Apparel and Textiles - Gret Atkin, 1989; TR-10937 (Box 89)
- Series VI. Conferences, In-service Programs, Retreats, Workshops, Resource Manuals
  - Annual Extension Conference-Kansas, 1946-11 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Workshop in Human Development-Human Relations for Extension Workers, 1955 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Family Life Conference, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Family Life Conference, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 45)
  - Home Demonstration Conference, 1956 (Box 58, Folder 47)
  - In-Service Training Conference- Talk-"Extension Service Benefits"-A.H. Peterson, 1957 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Conference Between Cornell Staff and Agricultural and Technical Institutes, 1957-06 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Rural Development Workshop, 1959-05 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Extension Specialists' Workshop, 1959 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Urban Extension Workshop, 1960 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography of Educational Materials, 1960-1979 (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - Lessons on Laundering-including commercial publications (1918-1979), 1960-1969 (Box 86, Folder 22-23)
  - Lessons on Textiles and Clothing-including articles and conference proceedings (1934-1952), 1960-1969 (Box 86, Folder 24-25)
  - Lessons on Clothing, 1960-1969 (Box 86, Folder 26)
  - Lessons-Make a Dress and Stretch in the Wardrobe, 1960-1969 (Box 86, Folder 27)
  - Clothing and Women's Role from 1840 to the 1960s and Figure Flattery -slide scripts, 1967 (Box 86, Folder 28)
  - Lessons on Sewing, 1960-1969 (Box 86, Folder 29)
  - Nutrition Education-Teaching Material, 1970-1979 (Box 86, Folder 30)
  - Presentation-"Cooperative Extension Service As it is Today"-by A.E. Durfee-Associate Director-New York State Extension Service, 1963-05 (Box 58, Folder 44)
  - Extension Conference, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - "Organizing for Program Implementation"-Conference, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 46)
  - Kerker Extension Study, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Kerker Report: A Management Study, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Community Resource Development Land Use Educational Program, 1969-10 (Box 85, Folder 40)
  - Population Affairs and New York State - Sources and Resources, 1972 (Box 85, Folder 41)
  - "Obesity and Overweight" - Reference Notebook for Agents, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1975-1976 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1976-1977 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1978-1979 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1980-1981 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1981-1982 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1983-1984 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1984-1985 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1985-1986 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Program Development Reference Manual, 1986-03 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Extension Faculty Resources, 1988-1991 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Extension Program Review Resources, 1992-05 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Extension Conference, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - County Law 224- Subdivision B, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Action and Renewal- People and Programs, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Agricultural Programs Handbook, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - Extension Home Economics- Program Leader Orientation Trainer Workshop, 1982-01 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Extension Home Economics- Program Leader Orientation Trainer Workshop, 1982-01 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Management Workshop, 1983,1985 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Educating in the Electronic Age, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Nutrition and Quantity Food Service Manual - New York City Program, 1986-08 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension Partners in Extension, 1986 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Campus Experience for Volunteers, 1987-1989, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Meeting the Needs of the 21st Century, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, 1988-2000 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Professional Leader's Conference, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Working with Single-Parent Families- Facilitator's Guide- Manual for Conducting Workshops- by Florence Cherry, 1980-1989 (Box 65, Folder 24)
  - Caring- Guide for 4-H Leaders and Members in 4-H Community Development Projects- by Florence Cherry, 1980-1989 (Box 65, Folder 25)
  - School-Age Care Credential- New York State, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 26)
  - School-Age Care Credential- New York State, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 27)
  - Conference Flyers, 1990-1999 (Box 65, Folder 31)
  - Heart Health Program, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting New York State Regulations for School Age Child Care- Workbook for School Age Child Care Programs- by Kathryn Sanger, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 32)
  - Resource Manual for School Age Child Care Managers- by Kathryn Sanger and Jennifer Birckmayer, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 33)
  - Resources for Working with Six-Nine Year Olds- In-Service- by Jennifer Birckmayer, 1991 (Box 65, Folder 34)
  - Inservice Program- "Issues and Strategies for Communicating Food and Water Quality Risks", 1991-01 (Box 65, Folder 35)
  - Child Care Notebook- by Polly Spedding, 1992 (Box 65, Folder 36)
  - Caring for Young Children- Teen Notebook- by Florence Cherry (Box 65, Folder 37)
  - Handbook for Workshop Leaders Training Child-Care Staff to Work With Five-to-Nine Year Olds- an addendum- by Martha Frost, Rosaleen Mazur- Spring 1992 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Meeting New York State Regulations for the Registration of School Age Child Care Programs- An Orientation Guide by Jane Gore, 1992 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Workshops, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Training School-Age Child Care Staff- Handbook for Workshop Leaders, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Training School-Age Child Care Staff- Handbook for Workshop Leaders, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Training School-Age Child Care Staff- Handbook for Workshop Leaders, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Retreat - Director's Council, 1995 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Families and Food: New Directions for Family Programming in Cornell Cooperative Extension - Resource Notebook, 1995-05 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - School Age Child Care - Brochure, 1996 (Box 85, Folder 35)
  - Food Stamp Nutrition Education Program- Child Assistance Program, 1996-10 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Food Stamp Nutrition Education Program- Child Assistance Program, 1996-10 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Food Stamp Nutrition Education Program- Child Assistance Program, 1996-10 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Learning About Early Adolescent Development- (LEAD)- Training for Adults and Teens Who Work With 9-14 Year Olds- by Sally Jo Crosiar, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Activities, Resources, 1980-1989 (Box 85, Folder 42)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Initial Proposal, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Timelines, Flyers, Resources, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Annual Report and Executive Summary, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Interim Report, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Notes on Volunteering; Year Two Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers - Final Report, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers- Final Report, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Healthy Families - Meeting Minutes, Participation Report, Annual Report, 1993-1995 (Box 85, Folder 43)
  - Healthy Families - Progress Report and Plan of Work, 1993 (Box 85, Folder 44)
  - Healthy Families - Report - Original, 1994 (Box 85, Folder 45)
  - Healthy Families - Report - Year 2, 1994-10-1995-09 (Box 85, Folder 46)
  - Healthy Families - Report - Year 3, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 47)
  - Healthy Families In-service Workshop, 1994-1997 (Box 85, Folder 48)
  - Project EASE (Exploring Aging Through Shared Experiences) by Karl Pillemer, Stephen Goggin, Susan Matson, John Gerecitano, Edith Lessegard, Ruth Raimon-Wilson, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Promoting Women's Health Across the Generations - Teleconference, 1996-1997 (Box 89, Folder 29)
  - In-Touch Science Proposal, 1996-1997 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - In-Touch Science Proposal - Final Report, Evaluations, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - In-Touch Science - Photographs, 1996-2002 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Seminar on Wheels, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Building Blocks for Toddlers (BBT) and Healthy Families (HF), Joint BBT/HF Meeting, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Campus Experience, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Conference Management Team, 1999 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Vision of Engagement, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Pathways to School-Age Quality Conference, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Faculty with Expertise in Children, Youth, Families and Communities and Related Supporting Staff, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Resources representing Cooperative Extension and Human Development, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Resources representing Cooperative Extension and Human Development, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Resources representing Cooperative Extension and Human Development, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Retreats - Administration Planning, 2002-2003 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - School Age Child Care and General Child Care Development Assistance Final Report, 2001 (Box 65, Folder 30)
  - Conference - Quality of Life for Individuals and Families Program Council (2003);Program Council-memos and proposals, 2001-2003 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Conference paper "Land Grant Universities and Extension into the 21st Century:Renewing the Covenant" by George McDowell, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Youth Develoment Program Council Conference, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Retreat - Faculty, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Certification for Youth Workers: A New York State Perspective, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Marketing Manual, Undated (Box 86, Folder 6-7)
  - Empower New York- Exploring Credit/Debt Management Issues - Workshop Manual, 2005 (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - Empower New York - Energy Use Management and Financial Management Workshops, 2005 (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - Empower New York - Energy Use Management and Financial Management Workshops, 2005-09; CD-3240 (Box 89)
- Series VII. Correspondence
  - Lincoln D. Kelsey Files
    - C.U.R.W. (Cornell United Religious Work) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - C.U.R.W. (Cornell United Religious Work) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - C.U.R.W. (Cornell United Religious Work) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Missionary Material (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Missionary Material (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - New York Christian Rural Fellowship Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rural Situation (Background Material of Interest to Rural Ministries) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Christian Rural Fellowship (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Christian Rural Fellowship Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Christian Rural Fellowship Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Near East Foundation (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Near East Foundation -- Program Committee (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Near East Relief (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Near East Foundation Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Extension's Part in Soil Conservation (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Bartlett Carry Club (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Radio Addresses (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Director's Correspondence
    - Directors' Letters to Associations, 1990-1999 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Director's Correspondence, etc., 1995-2000 (Box 49, Folder 47)
    - Director Lucinda Noble material, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - Deans and Directors-Correspondence, 1986-2001 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Director's Council, 1996-2000 (Box 49, Folder 57)
    - Associate Director Margaret Smith Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 73, Folder 15-16)
    - Director D. Merrill Ewert Correspondence, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Director D. Merrill Ewert Correspondence, 2001-08-2001-12 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Director D. Merrill Ewert Correspondence, 2001-01-2001-07 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Directors-Correspondence, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Directors-Correspondence, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Directors-Correspondence, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 22-23)
    - Strategic Directions- Implementation Plan, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 58)
    - Revitalizing Cornell Cooperative Extension- Second Draft, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 59)
    - Committing to Excellence, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 60)
    - Endowed Chair in Extension, 1986-1991 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Extension- Friends Committee: Notes Endowment Fund, 1988-1998 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Extension's Blueprint for Volunteer Excellence, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Criteria for Quality Extension Education Programs, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Extension Administration in the 1990's, 1992 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Reducing Risks for New York Communities, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Interview with Lucille Call Cunningham (Dean David L. Call's mother) regarding her experience with HE Extension, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence
    - Proposed book on Extension by H.W. Hochbaum and L.R. Simons and Cornell Farm Study Courses in Farm Bureau Leadership, 1920-1923 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Organization Campaign Material for County Agricultural Agents, 1928 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Conversations with Francille Firebaugh and Daryl Lund, 1997 (Box 85, Folder 36)
- Series VIII. Associations (County, State, National)- Historical Material
  - Albany County, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 38)
  - Broome County-Agricultural Conference Committee, 1930-1938 (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Broome County Study-"Land of the Future" -report by O. Cleon Barber, 1948-1953 (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Broome County Extension Program for Land and People not on Commercial Farms-Advisory Committee, 1949-1961 (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - Broome County-Forest Resources, 1952 (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Broome County Rural Development Program-Outline of Work Areas and Activities, 1955-1956 (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Broome County Rural Development Program- Plans of Work and Council Tour, 1955-1958 (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - Cayuga County Program; County Program Committee, 1928-1929 (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - Erie County-Home Bureau, 1931-1933 (Box 83, Folder 22)
  - Jefferson County-First County Programs Committee, 1928-1929 (Box 83, Folder 23)
  - Livingston County, 1965-1969 (Box 50, Folder 39)
  - Monroe County, 1957-1968 (Box 50, Folder 40)
  - Nassau County, 1962-1970 (Box 50, Folder 41)
  - New York City (I), 1970-1984 (Box 50, Folder 42)
  - New York City (II), 1970-1984 (Box 50, Folder 43)
  - Niagara County, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Oneida County, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Onondaga County, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Ontario County, 1964-1968 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Orange County, 1965-1969 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Orleans County, 1947-1951 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Oswego County, 1963-1969 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Otsego County, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Rockland County, 1968-1969 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Saratoga County, 1957-1962 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Schenectady County, 1967 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Schoharie County, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Schuyler County, 1969 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Seneca County Program Committee, 1928-1929 (Box 83, Folder 24)
  - St. Lawrence County-Study of 4-H Club Local Leadership by Bert Rogers, 1939 (Box 83, Folder 25)